well,
ну-ка
good day ukraine, the city of their militia, the
добрый день украины город их милиции
high city of russia
выского города россии
izhevsk izhevsk is oppressed yes
ижевска ижевска это угнетена да
we specially chose ukraine did you
мы специально выбрали украины ли
accidentally swim in the
случайно купался в
usa on propolis you may have some
сша на прополиса вы может есть какие то
questions about ukraine no questions no
вопросы по украине нет вопросов никаких
no i have questions and mugs you
нет у меня есть вопросы и кружки вы
look i ask  how do you feel about the
смотрите я спрашиваю как вы относитесь к
war in ukraine,
войне в украине
why is it pointless, honestly, I
ну чего это бессмысленно честно ну я то
understand that it is pointless, so you
понимаю что это бессмысленно вот вы
think, and you did the right thing shavlo
считаете и правильно сделала шавло
shumilov was looking for ukraine or wrong
шумилов искал украины или неправильно но
for
произошло какое-то не connect и из-за
this, the comfrey suffers not the end,
этого страдает окопника не конец
look there is one state from a friend
смотрите есть одно государство из друга
no rights whatever the rope
никаких прав какой бы там ни канат не
was not
был не
fell in love with Putin Zelinsky Zelensky there
влюбился путин зелинского зеленский там
he doesn’t want to talk to him like that and
ему не хочет с ним разговаривать так и
Putin attacking what difference does it make
путин нападая какая разница у нас есть
our country what could be the reasons
наша страна какие могут быть причины
to attack  cocaine and
чтобы напасть на нашу страну кокаин и
connect should have no reason for this to our country,
connect должен бы каких причин для этого
that is, you are so clearly like against
то есть вы так четко типа против
Ukraine
украины
that suffers from this and the UK
от этого страдает и украины и россии
Ukraine suffers more gratuitous Ukraine suffers more
дармовых украина страдает больше на
Ukraine was attacked here people are dying
украину напали у нас тут умирают люди а
and Russia suffers
у россии чем страдает у
more than 300 sanctions what we have more than 300 sanctions to
нас больше 300 санкций
quickly get to Ukraine children
быстро доехать в украине умирают дети
people are dying and in Russia products have risen in price
люди так а в россии подорожали продукты
and closed there it
и закрыли там
turns out a new one so just who has
получается новый так что просто кто вот
gone now  under the contract, they thought that
пошел сейчас по контракту они думали что
they would be sent to war, they were sent to
их отправят на войну на их отправляет на
war the shortest of all, it’s just that
войну короче всех просто вот они уже вот
after February they went on a contract, and
после февраля пошли на контракт да и
I think depriving no of the righteous, yes, earlier on a
думаю лишив нет праведного ага раньше на
contract, and now a military
контракт и вот началась военные
special operation began, they were sent here
спецоперацию их отправили сюда
so they can break the contract
так они могут разорвать контракт
you  did it well new people still
ты сделал хорошо новые люди все равно
go to some contracts now or not
идут какие-то на контракт сейчас или нет
now there are less on the contract
сейчас меньше стало на контракте че
no one wants
никто не хочет
[laugh] a
[смех]
contract for three months maximum
контракт на три месяца максимум у
we have a joke
нас дайте у нас есть такой прикол что за
that parents are paid for these deceased
погибшего выплачивают родителям какую-то
there they put some kind of family that they
там сунули какая-то семья была что
bought a fret viburnum and the
купили ладу калину и
plan is this money, yes, this is
плана эти деньги да это это
unrealistic,
нереально
because we will
потому что у нас
grow up thanks for the sea
вырастит спасибо за морской
officer Morshin, I think it’s our joke that
офицер моршин я думаю это наши прикол
drives when it really happened
гоняет когда это реально такое было
in the ask, these are acquaintances to her who
в аске это знакомые ей-то которые
fought, or
воевали или
well, a
ну вот
relative was going to collect it already,
родственник собирался его собирали уже
but something went very wrong, I went
но что-то весьма пошла не так я поехала
in the sense of collecting the background voluntarily went to the
в смысле собрал фон добровольно ходил
market, no soldier  and in the same place send all the
рынке нет военно служащий и там же всех
military personnel to if
военнослужащих отправляйте по если на
you want to retire, then like all of you already see the
пенсию хочешь то типа все тебя уже виде
argument so warmly the pension is that the little one
аргута так тепло пенсия то что маленькая
was going there more than
собирался там больше
50000 they themselves these 7 years I’m
50000 они же сами вот эти 7 лет я
buying
покупаю
you by the way here you and Sasuke are you and you
вы кстати вот вы и саске вы с вами
Russians are you bastards  Russians I am
русские ли вы [__] русские меня
Udmurt Tatar and you are Russian Russian
удмуртской татарка а вы русское русская
well I have Korean roots armchair
ну у меня есть корейские корни кресле
this is Spain but how, for example, did you
это испания а как как вот например вы
end up in Udmurtia if your parents are
попали в удмуртию если у вас родители
Russian and Koreans so go by roots how
русские и корейцы так идут корнями как
do you bend the lari fell down
вы выгнуть упали
hear grandfather was Korean yes well
лари слышь дедушка был корейцами да ну
how is he in  I got to Udmurtia, but honestly
как он в удмуртию попал а вот и честно
I don’t know,
не знаю
she was to ask what color and
она была спросить какой цвет и
how did you get into, and
как ты попал в а
you are a Tatar, her Tatar is Markov’s tapirs, they
вы татарка ее татарка тапиры маркова это
live close to Tatarstan, close there,
близко живут на татарстан близко там
and
недалеко и
after all, geographers and all peoples already
уже ведь уже географии и всех народов
know Russian or Tatar
знают русский язык или татарский
Tatar, but I don’t know at all, I
татарский а вообще не знаю
’m so clean there, hello,
я так чисто там здравствуйте
all that, but
все такое а
[laughter]
[смех]
few people speak Udmurt
разговаривать все мало кто разговаривает
when only a visiting Russian comes
когда только приезжий русский приезжают
from the cities, then they bar me in Russian
с городов то они там бар меня на русском
at schools and don’t study the Udmurt language hard, no
получается в школах и жестко не изучают
, I don’t have Glinsky to
удмуртский язык да нет там глинский на
choose from, it
выбор нет у
’s just when relatives come
меня просто когда родственники приезжают
here to the
вот
village there with Sharkan, otherwise that’s all  these are the plans of
деревне там с шаркан а то все эти план
grandparents to speak calmly
бабушка дедушка разговаривать спокойно
in Udmurt,
на удмуртском
and
а
why in schools you don’t know the
почему в школах не знаете
concept of them, no one
понятия о них никто не
can, on the contrary, not talk because
может наоборот не разговаривать из-за
they don’t teach
того что не учат
children, it turns out we Russify the
детей получается русифицируем
Maya of a small age, so every
майя маленького возраста так с каждым
year less and less
годом все меньше и меньше бабушек и
grandparents spoke up to
дедушек говорила до на
in their native language and from the thing it turns out
своем родном языке и от вещь получается
that all all nations do like so
что все все нации делают типа так
conditionally Russian,
условно русскими
that is  Tatars and stands as Russians Udmurts
то есть татары и стоит русскими удмурты
stands as Russians Chuvashs stands as Russians
стоит русскими чуваши стоит русскими так
and lived there 150 nationalities so now everyone has
и жила там 150 народности так теперь все
become Russian
стали русскими
now she wants to Russians not the majority
сейчас хочет она русским не большинства
began to learn the
начали учить
Russian majority began to teach where,
русский большинства начали учить где ну
well, there, for example, here are some who
вот там вот например вот некоторые же
learn Chinese and Japanese types, the most
учат китайский и японский типа самый
common and  the Japanese and Chinese have
распространенный и японцы и китайцы не
no less begun to learn Russian,
более менее начали учить русский язык
they are preparing to weld Siberia
они готовятся сибири сваривать
[laughs]
[смех]
from there there will be a Chinese People's
от идет там будет китайская народная
Far Eastern People's Republic,
дальневосточная народная республика
but
а
have you been to Russia in any other
вот вы в россии бывали в каких еще
region of
региона
furnaces in St.
печей в питере недавно была
- they were not very
на дальнем востоке где-то были не очень
far away and it turns out that you have a country such
далеко и получается у вас страна такая
that some parts, that is, the population of one
что одни части то есть население одной
part, does not communicate with the population of the
части никак не общается с населением
other, rush hours different countries,
другой часы пик разные страны на
it’s good, it’s good, it’s easier and easier that
это хорошо это хорошо легче и легче что
it fell apart into different republics,
она развалилась на разные республики те
then they lived in the far  in the east and
себе потом жили в дальнем востоке и
theses in St. Petersburg it’s
тесей в питере
not enough for the Chinese not to conquer you, they
мало чтобы китайцы вас не завоевали
will hold a special
проведут специальную военную операцию
say you have a military operation there, the Nazis see Izhevsk
скажешь у вас там нацисты вижу ижевске
gluing to the Koreans will come, they will say protection from the
клеить в корейцы придут скажет защиты от
Korean population,
корейского населения
I won’t get to us, they’re very far away,
не не доеду до нас им очень далеко а
why are the Chinese they are such guys,
почему китайцы они такие ребята
is it necessary to go on foot,
так ли да надо пешком пройду
maybe you have a question about Ukraine,
может у вас есть это вопрос про украину
stones,
камни
Ukrainians, if  and chat with such
украинцы вот если и пообщаться с такими
teenagers like it’s just Russian
подростками типа вот просто русские
Ukrainians talking flow this is Ukraine
украинцы общаются течь это украины
Ukrainians are somehow more aggressive towards
украинцы как-то более агрессивна к
Russians blouse meridia,
русским настроены blouse меридия
for example, we turn on not youngsters, all
например включаем не малолетки все
Russians, on the contrary, are ticking by, you
русские наоборот мимо тикают ведется вы
just don’t communicate with Russian
просто не общаетесь с русскими
youngsters and their flag is lit up Russia
малолетками и у них светятся флаг россия
sees a  ukraine and immediately shout
видит а украина у и сразу кричат а
why our view of valuable soversenno I will
почему наши взгляд ценного soversenno я
explain let's think about how you
поясню давайте подумаем вот как вы
think why children from ukraine are angry with
думаете почему дети из украины злятся на
you when they see that you are from russia
вас когда видя что вы из россии
like that the war will be officially yes that
типа то что война будет официально да то
is, if the child's
есть если у ребенка
relatives died if the wounded if the
родственники погибли ли раненый если
child  should the bomb shelter run if the
ребенок должен бомбоубежище бегать если
child moved to another city
ребенок переехал в другой город потому
because his city will be bombed  how
что его город разбомбят у как он будет
will he think, but when, in fact, they
вот как думать но с когда по фактам они
are to blame that this is how the new
виноваты же что так получилось новые
citizens of the country turned out, this is done on your behalf
граждане страны это от вашего имени и
and you are silent because you are
делается и вы молчите из за того что там
afraid there or somehow expresses your
боитесь или там как-то высказывает свое
opinion publicly, you manage to
мнение публично вы получается
support
поддерживать эту
this one  look, let's give such a simple test
вот смотрите давайте такой простой тест
to understand whether you support the war
дам то чтобы понять поддержите вы войну
or do not support the eyes of Crimea, our
или не поддерживает очей крым наш
[laughter]
[смех]
cream is the territory of Ukraine, the one that is
крем это территории украины та которая
temporarily occupied by the Russian
временно оккупирована российской
Federation from the documents, and also
федерации из документы он а также
that they say that the
которые говорят что
Russian Federation occupied Crimea and
российской федераций оккупировала крым и
should leave
должна покинуть
, we don’t understand about it  but shout that
об этом не разбираемся на но кричите что
Crimea is ours before they say they say that
крым наш до поговорят на говорят что
Crimea is ours, that is, it turns out that the cream was
крым наш то есть получается крем был был
Ukrainian so Russia temporarily
украинский так россии во временно
captured it and now you look like Crimea is
захватила так и теперь вы выглядите
ours so maybe if it’s how much
крымнаш так может если это сколько уже
Crimea is already then
крым то
look out when our old world
вон смотрите когда наша старая мировая
war was in the thirty-ninth year  so up to 45
война в тридцать девятом году так до 45
years before also captured some
года до тоже захваченные были некоторые
money
деньги
6 years more than six years here 8 you can
6 лет больше шести лет вот тут 8 можете
there and  10 will be occupied, but all the same,
там и 10 будет оккупирован но все равно
from this fact of occupation, not
от этого факта оккупации не
if I come and take your apartment,
если я приду и заберу вашу квартиру
I will kick you out and sit there 8, this is
выгоню вас и просидел там 8 не это все
still considered protection, my hut
еще считается защита моя хата
turns out right, no matter
получается право независимо от того
how long you keep the occupied
сколько вы продержите оккупированную
territory
территорию
in the history lesson, I sit for a year as a
на уроке истории сидим года я как
teacher  we can deduct you for the transfer,
преподаватель вас вычеты так на передачу
maybe after all, the war has been going on since the age of
можем может все-таки война идет с 14
14 due to the fact that Russia wants to
года из-за того что россия хочет
restore some kind of empire, that is,
восстанавливать какую-то империю то есть
some fool in the Kremlin, so you wanted to
какой-то дурачок в кремле так ты захотел
restore the empire, the empire of the empire, you
восстановить империю империю империи
don’t understand,
не понимаете
I’ll say this, I’ll
я вот так скажу
try to be more accessible  look russia is a
попробую доступнее смотрите россия
rich country
богатая страна
looking at gold gas and oil
смотря на золото газ и нефть
diamonds yes
алмазы да
where does all this money go gold gas
куда идут эти все деньги золото газа
oil diamonds
нефти алмазов
gold is
золото она хранится
not stored look russia sells gas in
не на смотрите россия продает газ в
europe all of europe there almost sells gas
европе всей европе там почти продает газ
it's a lot of money europe pays why
это куча денег европы платит почему
girls in prague live in warsaw  better
девушки в праге в варшаве живут лучше
than the girls in izhevsk
чем девушки в ижевске
good question
хороший вопрос
unknown you are watching the czech republic small czechs i dont
неизвестно вы смотрите чехия небольшая
have gas oil it is still
чехи у меня нету газа нефти она еще
p  pays back from russia they pay a woman for years and
покупает у россии платят бабу лет и
russia so and in russia there is so much gas oil
россии так а в россии столько газа нефти
but two girls in prague live better than
но две девчонки в праге живут круче чем
two girls running ski
две девчонки бежав ски
something that takes all this money for itself and
то что до забирает себе все эти деньги и
well, where does a lot of money
ну куда вот куда девается куча денег
go to russia it means she
приходит в россии значит она
gets so much  money from all over Europe
получает столько денег от всей европы
you can rebuild anything you want
можно отстроить все что угодно рабочие
freedom jobs blah blah in chocolate had
места свободы бла бла в шоколаде должны
to swim so don’t swim
были купаться так что не купаетесь
who let’s sing who takes all
кто давайте споем кто забирает себе все
this money to whom they go to the
эти деньги кому они уходят
president of course it turns out your
президенту конечно из получается ваш
president will taxi himself and well, his company
президент вырулит себе и ну его компания
in Runet is all  money from oil and gas for
в рунете все деньги с нефтегаза для же
this one is a rat
этот есть крыса которые
which of
какая из
us is the only one
нас только
you voted for in the presidential elections
вы за кого голосовали на выборах
and when it was voting earlier
а когда оно проходило голосование раньше
it was impossible for a long time they
нельзя было долго они
didn’t have time and for whom would you vote
не успели а за кого бы вы проголосовали
for Zhirinovsky
за жириновского
now I understand why girls in the right
теперь я понимаю почему девушки в праве
live better than  girls,
живут лучше чем девушки а
why did you like the socks, I liked my personal
чем вам же носке нравился мне личный
way since 2000, so we don’t know how
путь с 2000 года поэтому мы не знаем как
else that the
другое что
change of the bird to the pigment is mo  maybe you need
перемена птица пигменту может надо
to change yes, they just want to be
менять да они просто хотеть
good, let's mean in the exam I
хорошо давайте значит на экзамене ставлю
give you a test so pablo but they give you
вам зачет так пабло но дают домашнее
homework so you can
задание так
figure out how Russia occupied Crimea
разобраться как россия оккупировала крым
very interesting dialogue
очень интересный диалог
shows the
показы
essence of Russian juveniles not so far
суть российской молоди не такой далеко
beyond the wine and the alamo dulcimer wells,
за вино и колодцы аламо цымбал
but we each try our own exhibitions
но мы каждый сам пробовать свои выставки
I will not arrange here oksanka, I think,
не буду расставлять тут оксанка я думаю
and crystals for an hour,
и кристаллов час виду
subscribe, put likes,
подписывайтесь ставьте лайки
subscribe to 3 grams of pass, they will bring
подписывайтесь на 3 грамма пасе доведут
him our information franc of the
и руха ему наш информационный франк
word  glue
слова клей